<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Overview on Mutagen</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/</link><description>Recent content in Overview on Mutagen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016 – 2019 Mutagen IO, Inc.</copyright><atom:link href="https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/configuration/</guid><description>Configuration Mutagen has multiple levels of configuration that are merged together and locked-in at session creation time. These include built-in defaults, the global configuration file, command line configuration, and other configuration files. Once the configuration for a session is locked-in, it can&amp;rsquo;t be changed (without recreating the session). The purpose of this design is to prevent unintended behavioral changes from occuring for existing sessions when configuration files are updated.</description></item><item><title>Daemon</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/daemon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/daemon/</guid><description>Daemon At the core of Mutagen&amp;rsquo;s architecture is the Mutagen daemon. The Mutagen daemon is a per-user process that runs in the background, hosting and managing Mutagen&amp;rsquo;s synchronization and forwarding sessions. All of Mutagen&amp;rsquo;s session management commands actually dispatch their operations to the daemon and simply output its feedback. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not a user-facing component, understanding the behavior and lifecycle of the daemon is critical to using Mutagen effectively.</description></item><item><title>Getting started</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/getting-started/</guid><description>Getting started This guide aims to provide a basic introduction to Mutagen&amp;rsquo;s design and usage, with links to more advanced topics and features. While it focuses on Mutagen&amp;rsquo;s low-level primitives, the topics introduced here are a prerequisite for understanding Mutagen&amp;rsquo;s higher-level orchestration features.
Design Mutagen is designed and operated around the concept of individual synchronization and forwarding sessions. Each session operates between two endpoints, which in the case of synchronization are file system locations and in the case of forwarding are network endpoints.</description></item><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/installation/</guid><description>Installation Mutagen can be installed in two primary ways: via Homebrew and manually. Work is ongoing to bring packages to other platforms, so please check back regularly.
Homebrew Homebrew users (on both macOS and Linux®) can install Mutagen using the following command:
$ brew install mutagen-io/mutagen/mutagen Other platforms On other platforms, Mutagen can be installed by downloading the appropriate release and adding its contents to your path.</description></item><item><title>Names, labels, and identifiers</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/names-labels-identifiers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mutagen.io/documentation/introduction/names-labels-identifiers/</guid><description>Names, labels, and identifiers Mutagen provides three mechanisms for identifying and selecting sessions: names, labels, and session identifiers. These mechanisms can be used to identify sessions in listings and to select sessions when using session management commands.
Names Names are user-provided identifiers that can be attached to sessions. Names are optional and aren&amp;rsquo;t guaranteed to be unique. Each session can have only a single name. Names are particularly useful for manual usage, where a simple identifier for selecting sessions is desirable and the chance of name collisions is low.</description></item></channel></rss>