<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Transports on Mutagen</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/transports/</link><description>Recent content in Transports on Mutagen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016 – 2019 Mutagen IO, Inc.</copyright><atom:link href="https://mutagen.io/documentation/transports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docker® containers</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/transports/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mutagen.io/documentation/transports/docker/</guid><description>Support for Docker® containers Mutagen has support for synchronizing files and forwarding network traffic in and out of Docker® containers. This support extends to all Docker client platforms (Linux®, macOS, Windows, etc.), Docker daemon setups (local, remote, VM, Hyper-V, etc.), and Docker container types (both Linux and Windows containers are supported).
Requirements Mutagen requires the docker command to be in the user&amp;rsquo;s path. Due to its use of the -w/--workdir flag with the docker exec command, Mutagen requires a Docker client and daemon supporting API 1.</description></item><item><title>Local</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/transports/local/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mutagen.io/documentation/transports/local/</guid><description>Local Mutagen&amp;rsquo;s most basic transport provides support for synchronizing and forwarding to and from local filesystem locations and network endpoints, respectively.
Synchronization Local filesystem endpoints can be specified to the mutagen sync create command using their local path in either an absolute or relative format. If a relative path is specified, then it will be resolved relative to the working directory in which the mutagen sync create command is issued before being used to create the session.</description></item><item><title>SSH</title><link>https://mutagen.io/documentation/transports/ssh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mutagen.io/documentation/transports/ssh/</guid><description>SSH Mutagen provides support for synchronizing files and forwarding network traffic via SSH. This support extends to SSH clients and servers found on both POSIX and Windows systems.
Requirements Mutagen requires an OpenSSH client installation to be available on your system. This is the default for almost all POSIX operating systems, so you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need to do anything if you&amp;rsquo;re on macOS, Linux®, or one of the BSDs. Windows is supported as well, but please see the section on Windows support for more detailed information.</description></item></channel></rss>